I'm switching to Hermes. The vibe, the
mission, that alone sold me. But the
idea that the Hermes [music] agent grows
with you, is going to be better on day
30 than day one. That got me hooked.
Also, because I'm tired of fixing my
OpenClaw agents. And I'm not the only
one. This is now the fastest growing
GitHub project. It just topped OpenClaw
on the OpenRouter token usage. This
thing's taken the world by storm. It
can't be that good, can it? Is it
actually worth diving into yet another
tool, another harness? Let's talk about
it. I've been using it for a month, and
it's the only agent I felt comfortable
>> [music]
>> enough with to give to my wife. She
calls hers Honey, it's her BFF. I'm
telling you this thing is different. Let
me show you the five things, the five
reasons that made [music] me switch all
my stuff from OpenClaw to Hermes.
Actually, here's a teaser. The vibe, the
memory, the fact that it learns. Also,
we're going to build our very own IT
Hogwarts-themed troubleshooting wizard.
Easy for me to say. It's literally
magic. And also, went a bit too deep, I
think. I ended up talking to one of the
co-founders, Jeffrey Canel. So, you're
going to hear from him, too. Now, I'm
trying so hard to not use the phrase
right now, cuz I told you I would chill
out on that this year. But this,
it's something special. And I don't want
you burning tokens on tools that will
frustrate you. This one's worth your
time. So, get your coffee ready, it's
time to enter our self-improvement loop.
Self-improvement loop, what does that
mean? That's number four. It has to do
with the skill system, and is probably
the best reason on this list. But hold
on, don't go there yet. You haven't
installed it yet, and that's my goal
with this video. You're going to walk
away with Hermes running. And it's
actually pretty easy. They even have an
OpenClaw migration path. How nice of
them. But hey, I get it. You might be
where I was about a month ago. AI tool
fatigue. Don't give me another tool, I'm
full. Get it away from me. But News
Research, the company behind Hermes,
told me to try it, and I said, "Fine."
But let me hit you with number one real
quick. Look at this site. How can you
not try this for the vibes alone? We're
going to install this here in a moment,
don't worry. But just sit here and
appreciate this. This isn't some random
lobster project.
>> [laughter]
>> This is a company with a mission, a
purpose. I asked Jeff, one of the
co-founders, "What's up with this?
>> As much
>> we're online, you and me are like
terminally online, we're also like
creatures of this world and our our
sight and our taste and all that are
part of who we are. We put a we spent a
lot of time to make sure that we have
that that that that vibe feel behind it.
>> not just the vibe, it's who these people
are.
>> That that was our our origin story. It
was just a bunch of kind of hackers on a
Discord
trying to figure out if we can make
open-source AI.
>> We'll hit that here in a moment, but
first we got to install this. To install
it, we just run this one command, but
where? You got to put it somewhere.
Thankfully, you can pretty much run this
anywhere. It's lightweight, built in
Python, but my favorite place to run
this sucker is in the cloud. Hostinger,
that's where I put my wife's agent. They
are the sponsor of this video and the
sponsor of getting you spun up on Hermes
as quickly as possible. Are you ready?
Quick sip of coffee.
Go out to
hostinger.com/networkchuckhermes.
Now, what we're about to do here is
install Hermes on a computer in [music]
the cloud. But again, you can install it
anywhere. I think it's actually going to
be Windows native here soon. And don't
worry, the tutorial I'm showing you
right now will apply for anything. Apart
from the Hostinger [music] stuff. But
here we are in Hostinger, and we could
do the quick deploy option if you want
to be really fast. But I prefer this
method. Don't click on that, instead go
up here to services. Click on VPS
hosting [music] right here. By the way,
a VPS is a virtual private server, fancy
talk for a computer
>> [music]
>> somewhere else. But it's always on and
always available and it's always
awesome. We'll choose our plan. KVM2 is
the choice. [music] It's a whole home
lab in the cloud. Run Hermes, run
OpenClaw, run Docker, I don't care. Do
whatever you want. It can handle it. And
yes, you can run Hermes and OpenClaw
side by side. Test them. Once you choose
your plan, and watch this.
Put in the coupon code networkchuck.
And watch magic happen.
Boom, it worked. Choose Ubuntu as your
OS, go through a few more steps, and
then wait for your VPS to brew. You
should land on the VPS dashboard, and
we're going to copy this command right
here. Copy. And then we'll launch our
terminal. Whatever OS you have, go to
your search bar, type in terminal,
launch that sucker. Oh yeah, best place
to be. Now, that's actually one of the
things I love about Hermes. This is a
bonus one.
Is they actually do make it fun in the
terminal, not just a messaging app. And
they do have that, too. We'll paste our
command,
type yes to accept all fingerprints, and
then put in the root password that you
set up earlier.
And we're in. Right now, we are remoted
into or logged in to a computer in the
cloud. And this is where we're going to
install Hermes. And again, this is going
to be pretty easy. Let's go out to
Hermes and grab that one-line command I
talked about. There it is. Click on
copy, you're back to our terminal, paste
that in, and go.
It's going to do its thing.
Coffee break.
Ah, this is my favorite part of the
videos, honestly, watching stuff scroll
across the terminal while sipping
coffee.
Mhm, it's therapy. Hey, while you're
waiting, have you hacked the YouTube
algorithm today? Let's make sure you do.
Hit that like button, subscribe,
notification bell, comment. You got to
hack YouTube today. Ethically, of
course. Now, what we're about to do
when this finishes up is we're going to
create our IT agent. And this is
something actually I got inspired by
from Jeff over at Newest Research. They
got a dog-food mentality there. They use
their tools. I asked them like, "How do
you use it?" He's like, "This example."
>> So, we actually have our agents in our
Discord channels and have them running,
and we talk to them like they're team
members, basically. And there's just a
Hermes agent who's like the the the
developer, you know, the the system
admin. So, if someone comes into our
Discord and says, "Oh, something this
happened. I got this error message."
We're able to just talk to the Hermes
agent. And what's really amazing and is
that through having just done this, that
agent has built up a huge skill set of
skills particularly related to debugging
our infrastructure.
>> When he told me that, my brain exploded,
and I said, "That's what I'm doing."
We'll talk more about their example
later. I'll show you some stuff.
No, the vibe. Come on, that was cool.
Okay, we're here. Time for quick setup.
Hit enter. The first step is choosing
our inference model, or the brain.
Similar to Open Claw, Hermes is a
harness. It's a set of tools that will
use whatever LLM you want. If you want
to go local with LM Studio, do it.
Hermes is really good with it,
especially the quant model. Want to go
frontier? Open router's good, but my
favorite one to start with is the OpenAI
Codex. Why? Well, because you can use
your ChatGPT subscription with this.
Most of us already pay for ChatGPT. And
without paying any more money, you can
use ChatGPT as the brain for Hermes.
Hey, Chuck from the future here.
Something epic just happened. This, Grok
partnered with Hermes, and you can use
this as a Use your Grok subscription
with Hermes. Just another option, and
it's pretty powerful. Let's try it out.
Hit enter, and all we got to do is copy
this URL, paste that into our browser,
get logged into our ChatGPT account or
OpenAI account, and then grab this code
that Hermes gave us, and paste that in
here. Click continue, and that was it.
Pretty hard, huh? Login successful. Then
we'll choose our model. Grok 5.5, it's
the smartest. Select your terminal back
end. Keep it local for now, but just
know you can run it remotely. That's a
whole thing. Then finally, set up
messaging. Let's go ahead and do that.
Here you have options. We're going to go
with Telegram cuz it's the easiest, but
you can do any one of these. Also noting
that it has less options than you would
see with OpenClaw. Why? You'll start to
see this develop as kind of the
mentality behind News Research and
Hermes. Instead of supporting
everything, they'd rather make the
experience great with a few options.
Now, obviously, this is more than a few.
Let's go Telegram. Hit space to select,
hit enter, and we're almost there. This
part actually is really easy.
It's asking you for a Telegram bot
token, and to talk to somebody named The
Botfather. If you're not already a
Telegram user, become one, and open up
Telegram. Search for The Botfather. He's
going to help us create a new bot.
Open.
Click on create a new bot.
And let's name our bot. Mine's going to
be Ron Weasley. That's my IT wizard. By
the way, you're going to watch me walk
through every step of making Ron an IT
wizard in my company. Legit. Give him a
username. Must be unique.
And it must end in bot. Nailed it.
Create bot.
That was it.
Now, that little pixie dust thing, we're
going to copy that. Click on copy.
That's your token. Paste that right here
in the terminal, hit enter, and we're
almost done. This is a security measure
where you can tell your Hermes agent,
"Hey, only talk to me. Don't talk to
anybody else. Ignore everyone else. I'm
the user now." Oh, sorry, that was lame.
We're going to go with it. We're going
to talk to one more bot before we can
talk to our bot, the user info bot. We
need our username from Telegram. So,
we'll find the user info bot.
And usually when you just start talking
to him, you'll get your user ID just
like this. Copy that. Paste it. If you
want to add more, you can. For example,
my wife's agent Honey, I can talk to her
as well, not just my wife. We'll make
our user ID the home. Just hit yes.
We'll install the gateway as a systemd
service. If you're like, "What is
systemd?" I got a video on that right
here. Just hit yes for how the gateway
service should run in the background. If
you're on a laptop, go with the default
option. For VPS, let's choose the system
service. That's what I'm going to go
with.
Don't get mad at me in the comments.
But run it as which user? I'm going to
put root. Why? I'm on a cloud machine.
It's the only user I have right now.
It's who I am right now. And this
machine is going to belong to Ron. I
want him to own it.
He is the IT admin anyway. This is not
best practice or advice for any other
setup. But for our example, it's fine.
Start the service now? Yep. And we're
kind of done. And at this point, we can
talk to Hermes right here in the
terminal
or via Telegram. Let's do it in the
terminal. It's cooler. Hit enter, and
Hermes is
here. Let's see if he is here.
Hi.
He's alive. Also, notice at the top here
all the available skills that are
default built in. Talk about that here
in a moment at number four.
Foreshadowing.
Foreshadowing. Accident.
Let's try Telegram to make sure he also
is alive there. Let's talk to our new
user. Hi.
Typing.
Hi Chuck, what can I help you with
today? Now, at this point, if you've
never used an agent before, this is
magic, right? Enjoy. Go crazy. But if
this isn't your first agent, if you've
already used Open Cola, you're probably
going, "Chuck, uh
how's this different? This feels the
exact same." And honestly, at first
glance, it kind of is. But let me hit
you with number two. I discovered this
while walking the streets of Tokyo and
it's kind of insane. Transition.
>> [music]
>> I think memory is the reason people
switch to Hermes and stay. And they may
not even realize that's the reason.
Because under the hood, Hermes and Open
Claw kind of do memory in the same way.
With a few philosophical differences and
they make all the differences in the
world. Difference in the world. Let me
show you by building out our IT agent
right now. So, remember this is going to
be wrong. Now, if I say right now, "Who
are you?"
It's going to be generic. "I'm Hermes."
Let's change that. I've got a nice
prompt I'm going to feed him with, seed
him with. Here is who you are going to
be. Update any file, including your
soul, to reflect this going forward.
And then here's the massive prompt.
Essentially, he's Ron Weasley. He's
following in his father's footsteps of
falling in love with muggle technology,
specifically IT. Yada yada yada. It's a
backstory you can see in the description
below. Let's see what happens.
Now, notice it's already using a skill.
This is actually something I love about
it. It shows you the tool use happening.
Okay, identity locked. Let's test it.
I'm going to
do new, start a new session here. We
will approve that. And I'll say, "Who
are you?"
Nailed it. This is going to be fun.
Okay, so Hermes edited his soul.md file.
Big deal, Open Claw can do that. If we
cat that, here it is.
Still nothing amazing yet, but hold on.
Let's start building him out a bit more.
I'll tell him who I am. I'm number
checking, call me Chuck.
He'll also talk to other members of my
team when they have issues, blah blah.
Let's tell him that. Now, watch what
happens here. I think it's going to
happen here. I'm doing this live with
you. There. There it is.
>> [laughter]
>> Put it in the pensieve. Notice we have a
memory action here and it added it to my
user file. This file, let's go open it
real quick. We'll CD into our .hermes
directory
and then jump into
our memories directory. We'll LS there
and there it is. user.md. Let's cat
that.
This file is what Hermes will write
about you, what it learns about you, and
it curates this on its own. And that's a
key part. We're We're going to cover why
that's important here in a moment, but
let's keep adding. This is fun. I'll
give him some more information. I'll
tell him about the network
and a few other things.
With that information, let's see what
happens.
So, we added more to the user side. Let
me tell him more about him.
Ah, and there's the other part of the
memory. He added it to his memory file.
Let's go look at that. LS, there's a new
file there, memory.md. Let's cat that.
Notice the memory file is more about the
environment, where Ron is running, some
technical things. This will also be
curated by the agent. Now, those two
things, the user.md file and the
memory.md file, they're not
groundbreaking things. Like, Open Claw
has these, too. In fact, when you move
from Open Claw to Hermes, that's part of
migration is just taking those files
over to Hermes. The difference is how
Hermes uses these files. Now, both
Hermes and Open Claw will take these
files. And when you start a new session
with Hermes, boom, new session. The user
and memory file will be loaded into the
system prompt, so that when you talk to
your agent, it always has the most
relevant information about you and what
you're doing. Both Open Claw and Hermes
do that, but here's what Hermes does
that Open Claw does not do well. You'll
feel this, and this is why Open Claw
feels clunky and bloated on day 30
versus Hermes. Actually, Hermes does two
things. The first thing it does is it
has hard limits on the size of those
files. The user file can only be 1,375
characters. The memory file, 2,200
characters. Now, why does this matter?
Well, it forces the agent to be very
particular about what's going to be
loaded into its system prompt. Now, for
example, we were just talking with Ron,
and he was adding stuff to this memory.
And as we keep talking to him and adding
more things and talking and talking and
talking, that's going to get full. So,
what happens when it gets full? Well, he
has to delete something. He has to
curate it, guard what actually needs to
go in there, what needs to go in there.
And that keeps the agent focused. It
forces the agent to distill what is
actually important about interacting
with you and what you need. And that
actually matters a lot. Versus Open
Claw, which does have similar
mechanisms, but mostly it's going to end
up bloating itself over time if you
don't really watch it. This does it by
default. It does it without you even
thinking about it, and it did it when I
didn't even realize it was doing it. I
got a story for you on that here in a
moment. This is my wow moment with
Hermes. The second thing it does is it
nudges. By default, every 10 turns, I
believe it's every 10 turns, have your
Hermes agent fact-check me. It will run
a background agent to see if anything
that we've been talking about should
update the memory or user file. Most
agent infrastructures, including Open
Claw, only do this when you're about to
compact or start a new session. This
happens during the session with Hermes.
It's more active. This alone made it
feel pretty different, and it guards it
over time. But then I tried something
else. Watch this.
This This is crazy. I tried this. We'll
use the Hermes command line options.
We'll do Hermes
memory setup. Here we can configure the
Hermes memory, and right now by default,
we're just using built-in memory and
user. It also has a mechanism to search
your past sessions if it needs to. But
then we have these add-ons that do
something kind of insane. I'm not going
to dive too deep on this because that
could be its own video. In fact, I'm
probably going to make a video about it.
But I added this thing called Honcho.
You can run a Honcho server locally or
run it in the cloud. I tried it in the
cloud. So here's how this works, and
this is crazy. I talked to Hermes. My
agent's name is James, James Potter.
Every time I send a message, that
message is also sent to Honcho. Honcho
is a peer service. It's not Hermes. It's
kind of a plug-in that will start to
reason over what I'm saying, and it will
start to build out what's called a peer
card. Basically, who's Chuck? And it
gets to know me. Over time, as more and
more messages are sent, it will start to
make more conclusions and learn. But
that's not the cool part. The cool part
is still back at James. With Honcho
working in the background, when I send a
message to James, in his system prompt,
he's getting his user.md file, his
system.md file. Like keep in mind, these
are all very important because when
you're talking to whatever model it is,
Anthropic, GPT, it's going to start from
scratch. It's a blank slate unless you
fill its head with something when you
start talking to it. So, it has this
built-in stuff that we give it. But then
also, Hancho is configured to go, "What
does James need to know about Chuck?
Right now, in this moment, what context
would be important based on what Chuck
just asked?" This combo right here, I
can verify cuz I used Hermes for a month
with this setup. It's kind of crazy. Let
me show you what Hancho looks like
actually on the cloud.
Here are some conclusions it made about
me, like my daily habits, or that Cathy
does not like spice. And it builds up
this peer card, which I can't show you
completely, of my personality, my
traits, and my preferences.
Like this one. Trait: high friction,
technical procrastination, gravitates
towards tool building, wiring to avoid
high-stakes communication, or soul work.
Ouch. So, I was in Tokyo when I first
started using James. I would get up
early before everyone else, walk the
neighborhoods, and just have
conversations. It's good. I had some
breakthroughs. Now, to be fair, Hancho
is something you can actually plug into
Open Claw as well, but it's not as good.
It's not as much of a first-class
citizen as it is with Hermes. But
honestly, Hermes is pretty stinking
great even without this addition. All
this is kind of scary a little bit
because you're relying a lot on the AI
model to learn things and self-correct
itself. And should we allow it to do
that? I asked Jeff about this.
>> The models are smart like
get out of the way of the models
basically, you know? Like they're smart
enough, if we let them, to just be
figure out what it is that you want to
do.
>> [music]
>> So, at this point, we have our IT agent
Ron. He knows who he is. He's ready to
start working. We're about to give him
some skills. And actually, no, we're
not. You'll see You'll see. The way it
does this is so cool. But before we get
there, did you know that Hermes
was around before Open Claw? You didn't
know that? Me either. I was talking with
Jeff, the co-founder, and he told me
this.
>> So, actually Hermes Agent started out as
an internal tool that we wrote almost We
started it almost 6 to 7 months ago as a
tool we were using internally to like
prototype this recursive
self-improvement for model training. And
when OpenClaw came out, it was actually
kind of weird cuz we're like, we
actually already have this At the time
we were aware of the effect it would
have on the world. And when we saw what
what what what what what OpenClaw did,
we're like, we can give this out cuz we
have our own version. And honestly, when
we tried OpenClaw, I mean, I I hadn't
used it before, but some of the other
people on the team were and they're
like, this felt a little clunkier
compared to what we had internally.
>> I love that. They tried OpenClaw and was
like, wow, this is way clunkier than
what we have. Let's release our version
to the world cuz we think it's better.
And this is number three, by the way, of
the reason I switched from OpenClaw to
Hermes. It's the people and the story
behind this tool.
>> We are a group of researchers who found
[music] each other because we care about
making humanistic, censorship-free, and
democratic AI.
>> I think that's important, right?
Especially now in the day and age of AI,
I think who's making the tools, why
they're making the tools, and what
they're going to do going forward is
really important for us. And knowing
that Hermes was around before, it wasn't
just a reaction to OpenClaw, and that it
was built by AI researchers, people who
are building their own models, which I
don't know if you knew that. News
research, they literally were just a
bunch of hacker nerds in a Discord
training their own models, which was
also named Hermes. They still have their
Hermes models. Hermes Agent is separate.
But after talking with Jeff, I was even
more convinced that this company's
pretty cool, and I'm very happy with my
decision to switch to Hermes.
>> AI is not meant to replace you. It's
meant to make you be a better version of
you every day.
>> And by the way, a lot of what we said I
can't include in this video. It's just
maybe too long. So, if you want to see
that full interview, I'm actually going
to launch it first on the Network Chuck
Academy alongside a course we're
building for Hermes. I'm showing you the
basics here to get you up and running
and going crazy. There's a lot more you
can do. So, check it out link below.
Okay, now on
to number four. The most powerful thing
that Hermes does, it's the headline.
It's the grow with you thing that
everyone talks about, better on day 30
than day one. Watch this. We're going to
give Ron some tools, man. We're going to
make Ron powerful. We're going to give
him some skills, but Hermes does skills
in the weirdest way. Watch. It's going
to happen. Right now he's in the hosting
your cloud, right? He can't talk to my
IT stuff here in my studio. Not yet.
We're going to use TwinGate. It's a VPN.
It's a way to remote into my stuff and
it's amazing. I'll tell Ron, "Hey, I
need you to set up the headless TwinGate
client for access to my studio.
Here is your key.
Make it happen."
Now, I'm doing this live with you.
I'm hoping he'll do what I think he's
going to do here. Fingers crossed. He's
going to start working. He's going to
start building this.
And our video editor's going to blur out
my key. Done. Notice he added it to his
memory. Okay, cool. Now he's connected
to my network. That's cool by itself,
right? Search the network. See what you
can find. Oh, did you see that? There it
is. That's what I've been waiting for
right here. I didn't tell him to do
this. Self-improvement
review skill TwinGate client operations
created. Ron just made his own skill.
That's the power of Hermes.
It makes its own skills. The skill
system, which is sort of like the heart
of it, which is the ability for it to
crystallize once it's viewed how you
operate to take learnings basically and
and crystallize them down into a
like a a meaningful chunk that it can
then reuse. So, we sort of modeled it
after kind of how, you know, a crude
version of how potentially, you know, we
ourselves work, which is we struggle
through things. When we figure out ways
that solve hard problems, we we note
that down and then we iterate on those
successes. What? How powerful is that?
And that's a huge differentiator between
Open Claw and Hermes. With Open Claw,
it's all about finding skills in a
marketplace. Whereas Hermes is all about
building skills, repeatable workflows
based on your interactions with Hermes.
Now, Hermes does have a built-in skill
library that is curated by the Hermes
team.
>> One of the um pre-packaged skills that
we do ship is this uh GitHub PR review
um that is is in there. That skill
actually is like the result of Tecneum
having gone through thousands of PRs
manually and built up the review process
that we use internally for PR reviews.
And now it's like a very high-quality
crystallized PR system.
>> That's important because uh I don't know
if you remember, Open Claw, when it
first came out, dude, malware central.
Clawd Hub, where you could download a
bunch of Open Claw skills that the uh
community was uploading. Yeah, there was
bad stuff in there. Um Open Claw had a
bunch of CVEs, or vulnerabilities that
would get you hacked. As of this video,
Hermes hasn't had anything agent-related
hit it yet. And I think it's because of
this mentality right here. Also, it's
kind of the Hermes team philosophy,
keeping things very simple. But it's not
just the building of skills that's
pretty cool. It's the self-improvement
loop that I alluded to you at the
beginning of the video. Hermes just came
out with this, a thing called the
curator, which it will be an agent that
runs in the background periodically. And
it will review the current skills. It
will curate skills. It'll make sure your
skills are good. If there's a skill
that's not relevant anymore, it'll
remove it. It'll improve skills
as you're working with your agent. It
actually moves skills through an active,
stale, and archived state. And it exists
so that skills created via the
self-improvement loop don't pile up
forever. And by the way, this
self-improvement loop, this is the
mentality for when an agent will create
skills. How cool is this? Now, I want to
do a callback to that video I made on
Perplexity Computer. And one of the
things I said in that was that
because I couldn't change too much with
Perplexity Computer, I couldn't tinker
with it too much.
I was able to just be creative and
actually use it instead of sharpening my
ax all the time. Hermes, while I can
tweak it, it's certainly tweakable, it's
less. It also just kind of works and
does its own thing and figures things
out. Allow me to just work with it, tell
it to do things, and it figures it out.
Kind of in that same vein, and I think
that's why it's so successful for most
people. Like what Jeff said, we're kind
of just getting out of the agent's way.
>> Get Get out of the way of like them and
like let the models be smart, basically.
And it just give them the hand like the
the the model is the brain, right? We
just needed to give it the hands, the
feet, the fingers to touch the world in
an appropriate way, and then once it has
that haptic feedback, really, that's
what it is. Like the harness is the
haptic feedback to the model of the
world.
>> It's a weird thought, but it works. Oh,
back to Ron. He found a bunch of stuff.
He wants to do a deeper search.
Go for it, dude.
Now, while Ron's doing that here, I want
to go talk to Ron
in
uh Telegram. Start a new session here,
and let's do something fun. Built into
Hermes is a Home Assistant skill. I use
Home Assistant to run my studio. Let's
make some things happen. I'll tell him
to enable it first. I think it's
disabled by default. Brilliant. The Home
Assistant wanted to switch it on.
I love the way he talks. Let me give him
the IP address and key, and let's see
what he does.
And look at that. He's he's figuring
things out, saving it to his memory.
Okay, let's let's test it. Got that lamp
behind me. Let's tell him to turn it
off. Can you turn off Chuck lamp? See
what happens.
He did it!
>> [laughter]
>> I'll say, "Turn it on and make it blue."
Also notice, I'm talking to Ron in two
different places and he's doing two
different things. Ah, he did it!
>> [laughter]
>> Yes!
Ah, this is fun. One more thing. We have
automatic blinds in there. They're all
open. I want to if he can do this.
All right. I'm going to go
fill this and see what happens. Here we
go.
He did it.
What happened?
There's one in the kitchen.
He got it.
>> [laughter]
>> He found it.
I told you IT is magic.
Woo.
Back on the network side, Ron is wanting
some UniFi access. Should we give it to
him? Yes.
Let's see what happens. Now notice, this
is this is what I learned from the
Hermes team, from Jeff.
>> Rather than the hubris of being like, I
know exactly all the skills or I know
exactly all the things that you need,
like the models are smart like like get
out of the way of the models basically,
you know, like they're smart enough if
we let them to just be figure out what
it is that you want to do.
>> I don't have to bring on this fully
onboarded IT admin with skills that I
created and everything. No, I just bring
him on like a
person and say, "Hey, you need to manage
this thing. Go look at it. You need to
manage this thing. Go look at it." And
he'll figure it out.
Ah, this is the IT admin I was looking
for. Yes. I'll see you. I'm getting you
UniFi creds now. While you're waiting,
I don't know why I capitalized gear.
Uh research everything you can about
UniFi so you are ready to go. Now
notice, I'm not pointing these things
out because they're not new things to
the agent world, but it can delegate
tasks. It can do sub agents. It's a
fully functional agent harness. I'm just
honing in on the main things that make
it awesome. Also notice you can
interrupt, steer, or queue messages. So
if I send something right right by
default, it would interrupt him and go,
"Oh, oh, oh, what what does Chuck need?"
Instead, I'll just queue and say, "Here
is your UniFi API key."
All right, he finished his inventory,
realized he couldn't get very far
without using a password, but
self-improvement created a UniFi network
operation skill. Let me give him a user
account. Now, we'll come back to this.
We'll see how far he goes. But, we got
to move on to number five.
And this one
is just funny because it goes back to
the idea that Open Claw was kind of
clunky. Jeff's team said it themselves.
This felt a little clunkier compared to
what we had internally. And that was my
experience. When I initially set up Open
Claw, it was like, "Oh, this is so cool.
It's so powerful."
But, I don't know about you, but over
time, it kind of degraded. And it would
break. An update would break it, or it
just wouldn't respond. I'd be like,
"Hey, are you there? Are you awake?" It
became super frustrating, and it wasn't
a thing I wanted to give out to my wife
or my friends and family. It was one of
those things where you had to be an IT
person that knew how to troubleshoot it
because it was a project. And that's how
Open Claw feels. It feels like a
project. Whereas, Hermes feels more like
a product. And I got to tell you, I've
been using it. I I I could have made a
video a month ago about this, but I
wanted to give it some time. I wanted to
actually just see if it's cool.
I haven't had
I don't think I've had one issue.
Nothing I didn't cause myself.
And my wife is having a great time
talking to her friend Honey, who is
helping her with homeschool and diet
planning and and just managing the house
for six kids. Yes, we have six kids, six
daughters. So, number five, in case you
didn't realize it, was that Hermes just
doesn't break. The team behind this,
they're AI engineers. And I think that's
important, and their mentality behind
this matters. They're not just going to
add a bunch of features to make it
bloated or to compete with somebody
else. And sure, it has pretty much
feature parity with Open Claw. It just
doesn't allow a bunch of things that
shouldn't be there. They have a
philosophy coming into this, which is
kind of just get out of the agent's way.
Jeff told us earlier, or maybe he
didn't, I don't know if we included that
quote. We'll get out of the way with the
We're at a point now to where the AI
models we're getting, they're good.
Like, if we stopped getting new models
at this point, I think we would be at a
point where we could have AGI. What
matters the most now is using the right
harness, tweaking the tools around it to
make it awesome. Cuz Opus 4.7, GPT 5.5,
I mean, those things are good. And when
you use something like Hermes with it,
you really start to realize, "Oh my
gosh, you can do a lot more." Again, if
you want to hear more about the
philosophy behind Hermes, I talked with
the co-founder for a while. That
interview should be live right now on
the academy. Now, beyond number five,
Hermes is shipping features, like right
now. There's a Hermes dashboard. Look at
this. And if you want to learn how to do
this, by the way, we'll also have that
in the course. I can only show you so
many things here, but check this out.
You can get in here and look at your
skills and plugins. You can add more
agents, more profiles, add more models.
You can have auxiliary models, where you
can have one big model that does your
main thinking, but maybe have another
one that does research, or one that's
dedicated to delegation. They have
achievements, which is kind of fun.
Look at this. Again, the vibe is so
awesome. Let them cook.
Agent autonomy. And then, one of the
most powerful things they've released
recently is Kanban. You can actually set
up a task. You're like, "Create me as a
Pokémon card. You network Chuck, use my
likeness, make it an HTML page, make it
look awesome."
I'll assign it to default, cuz that's
the profile, and we'll create it.
And there it goes.
I mean, how cool is that? You can jump
into it and see the progress. I think I
hit a rate limit.
>> [laughter]
>> You can add comments. It will stop and
ask for human input if it needs it. And
it got blocked because I hit my usage
limit.
>> [laughter]
>> But you get the picture. Also, they just
came out their own computer use, which
allows it to control your computer. I
think it's still in preview, but man,
they're moving things along. It's
becoming very exciting. I'm kind of a
fanboy. I'm being honest. Like, it's
it's fun. I like the vibe. I like the
people. I'm not sponsored by them, but I
think they're really cool. Let me know
what you think. Like try Hermes. And you
can run Open Claw and Hermes side by
side. You can do your Open Claw
migration. You can do your test. I
converted. Are you going to convert? Let
me know in the comments below. That's
all I got. I'll get you guys next time.
Hey, you made it to the end of the
video. If you're new here, at the end of
my videos I like to pray for you, my
audience. I'm going to get some more
coffee real quick. Now, I know it's a
weird thing.
A YouTuber praying for his audience.
Why? Well, I believe in the power of
prayer.
Even if you don't.
And you know what? Just stick around.
You never know what's going to happen.
I'm not trying to force anything on you.
I just genuinely care about you and I
believe that this is a powerful thing.
So, let's do it. 1 2 3, pray.
God, I thank you for the person on the
other side of this camera, this screen.
Um I just thank you for who they are.
I thank you that they are passionate
about technology, that they're
interested in AI, and I pray you bless
that. I pray that right now with the way
the world is, with AI moving so quickly
that you will be able to calm them down,
let them not be too stressed,
and point them to the good things to
use. The things that will elevate them
as a human. The things that will
encourage them.
And let them not sell their soul to AI.
Let them not offload the things that
they need to do to AI. Help them figure
that out, God.
Equip them with the gifts they need.
Bless their families right now. Let
their families be uh prosperous and
blessed and healthy. Bless their
marriages and their children.
I pray blessings over them right now.
Bless them as they try all these new AI
tools, and I pray that through this
learning, through this
uh just tinkering,
that this will produce opportunities for
them they never even imagined. Job
opportunities. Um income opportunities.
Or just breakthroughs in their
relationships or just their own
thinking. I pray this over them, God.
And I thank you for them.
It's in Jesus' name I pray.
Amen.
Thank you for letting me do that.
I'll get you guys next time.